# DOMINIC L. MCKENZIE

148 Tyler Avenue ♦ Carteret NJ 07008 ♦ dominic.1.mckenzie@gmail.com ♦ (732)540-5523

#### **OBJECTIVE**

I am a quality driven Network Administrator and Developer with over 6 years of experience. I am seeking a Network Analyst position that will allow me to contribute to the growth and innovation of the company as I develop and utilize my technical, programming, project, and problem solving skills.

#### **EDUCATION**

# NEW JERSEY INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY (NJIT) — Newark, NJ

In progress of Bachelor of Science (B.S.): Information Technology: Web Applications; December 2016, expected, GPA 3.92

### MIDDLESEX COUNTY COLLEGE — Edison, NJ

Associate in Applied Science (A.A.S.): Computer Science: Network Administration, May 2013, GPA 3.57 Certificate of Achievement: Windows/ PC Support, May 2013

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

◆ CompTIA Network+

January 2015

Microsoft Certified Professional

**MTA**: Network Fundamentals July 2013

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

- OS: Windows XP, Vista, Windows 7, 8.1, 10, Server 2008 R2, Server 2012 R2, IOS, Android
- ◆ Programming Languages: SQL, C#.Net, JavaScript, mySQL, PHP, HTML5, CSS, JAVA, Visual Basic
- **Networking:** TCP/IP, LAN, WLAN, VPN, DNS, DHCP, DMZ, VLAN, WAN, FTP, SSH, Virtual Servers/Desktops; Hyper V; Remote Desktop; GoToMeeting

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### DATAMATICS MANAGEMENT SERVICES INC., Fords, NJ

#### Systems Implementation Specialist, 05/2013-Present

- Answers, evaluates, and prioritizes incoming telephone calls, voicemails, emails, and in-person requests for assistance from users experiencing problems with hardware, software, networking, and any other computer related technologies.
- Interviews client user to collect information about a problem and leads user through diagnostic procedures to determine source of error.
- Handles problem recognition, research, isolation, resolution, and follow-up for routine user problems, escalating more complex problems to the correct technical staff.
- Management of backup systems/ procedures and disaster recovery plans.

- Phone: (732) 540-5523 **Page 2**
- Configures and tests bio-metric and time clock hardware.
- Network Management, including the installation, configuration, troubleshooting, maintenance, and support of the Internal Network Infrastructure.
- Handles shipping, receiving, and tracking of hardware and or IT related inventory via UPS/ FedEx.
- Works with software development team in creating, testing, implementing, and maintaining various custom applications and programs.
- Logging and tracking of calls and emails using Microsoft Dynamics CRM.
- Calls hardware vendors to request service regarding defective products.
- Develops training support materials such as documents, exercises, and visual displays.
- Trains end users/ administrators on software and or hardware on-site or via the web.
- Writes or revises software/ hardware training documents and procedures for management review.
- Develop small programs in C#.
- Run queries in Microsoft SQL 2012.
- Analyzes and evaluates incident reports and makes written recommendations to reduce help line incident rate.
- Consults with technical staff to explain software errors or to recommend changes to programs.
- Asset management of IT/Network infrastructure inventory and hardware.

# QDX PATH ALLIANCE, Cranford, NJ

#### IT Support Specialist, 04/2011 to 11/2011

- Direct technical support for medium sized company with 125+ employees.
- Managed, updated, and backed up Inventory via software.
- Proficient in laboratory software: LabDaQ, LIS.
- Responsible for software updates, upgrades, backups, and maintenance of servers and network.
- Created and updated existing IT related policies and SOPs.
- Supervised and trained data entry personnel and data entry procedures.
- Assisted as part of a team in creating HL7 interfaces for new machines and EMR systems.
- Established remote connections to external client computers using Remote Desktop & LOGMEIN for troubleshooting, updating, support and maintenance.
- Provided professional help desk technical support for numerous clients.
- Responsible for shipping, tracking, and receiving via FedEx and UPS.

## FLEXTRONICS, Woodbridge, NJ

# Device Specialist, Customer Support Technician, 02/2008 to 03/2011

- Face to face programming, troubleshooting, repair, support, updating, and maintenance of IPhones, Androids, Blackberries, Windows Mobile devices, PDAs, phones, and tablets.
- Diffused customer escalations to ensure efficient and effective customer service.
- Responsible for opening and closing procedure of the technical service department.
- Selected to assist in the training of 13 new employees; recognized for world class experience to customers; earning 3 service awards.
- Responsible for answering technical support calls via telephone.